- Do not let this guy revive!
- Too late!
（隊長）
こいつだけは復活させるな！
（佐藤(さとう)）
遅い！
（高橋(たかはし)）
ハハハハッ…　行けぇ 佐藤！
Go, Sato!
（銃声）
ううっ！
（コウマ）
ＳＡＴ(サット)隊の状況連絡は？
- What's the status of the SAT unit!?
- Likely wiped out.
（曽我部(そかべ)）
恐らく全滅かと…
（下村泉(しもむらいずみ)）
ああっ…
（戸崎優(とさきゆう)）
駄目か
No good, huh?
（オグラ･イクヤ）
フッ ゲームセットだ
Game, set, and match.
（警官たち）
あっ…
（ざわめき）
（佐藤）
いやぁ 疲れたね
Whew, I'm beat.
（モニター音声:司会者）
佐藤の凶行で
多数の犠牲者が出た背景には―
There have been many casualties
at the hands of Ajin Sato.
But Grant Pharmaceuticals is also being
questioned for its responsibility...
グラント製薬の
責任も問われており
経営存続は危機的な状況です
以前から亜人の捕獲には
１億円とのうわさがあり…
This leads credibility to rumors of a 100
million yen reward for captured Ajins.
（北(きた)）
うん？　１億？
One hundred million?
（テレビ音声）
こちらが情報提供の対象となる―
Here is a list of all the Ajins
not currently in government custody.
政府の保護下にない亜人の一覧です
ああっ！　あのガキ…
That brat, I knew there was something.
やっぱり！
One hundred million yen bounty?!
あっ ちょっといいかい？
あ… 亜人を知ってる者(もん)だがな…
Yeah, listen.
I've got information on an Ajin...
（戸崎）
何度も申し上げているとおり―
Just as I've said several times...
逃走経路上に設置された
監視カメラは―
All the security cameras along
his escape route have been hacked...
全てハッキングされており
...and not one of them shows the Hat.
帽子の姿を捉えたものは
１台もないのです
（コウマ）
つまり “現状では帽子につながる
手掛がりは一切ない”と
So you're telling me
you don't have a single clue...
...as to the Hat's current whereabouts.
そういうことか？
（若井(わかい)）
ハッ 大失態だな　戸崎
What a failure, Tosaki...
（電話の着信音）
（泉）あっ…
（若井）
帽子に
やすやすと襲撃を許し―
You let the Hat's attack take place,
and then you just let him go.
その上 まんまと逃がすとは
もう 言い訳は…
There are no more excuses.
（泉）
戸崎さん！
永井圭(ながいけい)の潜伏先が―
Kei Nagai...
...has been found.
判明しました
AJIN: DEMI-HUMAN
Do you sleep well?
深く眠れるかい？
傷は癒せたかい？
Did your wounds heal?
Just cos' they say the night is lonely
夜が寂しいからって
無理して
誰かを愛さないで
You don't have to force yourself
To love someone
They say I'm dreaming
夢を見る事だって
咽び泣く事だって
They say I'm sobbing
知りもしないまま
死んでみたって
They say I tried to die without knowing
上手に隠れたかい？
息は潜めたかい？
Did you manage to hide?
Did you hold your breath?
今が苦しいからって
Just cos' they say it's tough now
You don't have to force yourself to change
無理して自分を変えないで
Even a brave savage
勇敢な蛮人だって
悩める子羊だって
Even a troubled lamb
回り道して生きているって
They are just wandering through life
目立たないように
So I don't stand out
So I can put up with it
堪えられるように
思考回路はまだ
止めないように
So my train of thought won't stop yet
Tonight run away, run a way
It's unbelievable
今宵 RUN AWAY  RUN A WAY
嘘みたいだ
誰かこの手
掴んでくれよ
Someone take my hand
The tomorrow we can't see
Doesn't have to come
見えない明日は来なくていい
今はただ 眠りたい
Now I just want to sleep
SATO, IT'S ALL YOUR FAULT!
Send everyone we've got.
とにかく
全ての人員を投入してください
今回ばかりは 失敗は許されない
We cannot afford to fail this time.
Yes, I'll let the Chiba police know.
（荒木(あらき)）
ええ 千葉県警には
そのように伝えてあります
But there aren't enough
tranquilizer guns--
ただ 麻酔銃の配備数が足りず…
（戸崎）
…でしたら 殺し続けてください
Then just keep killing him.
I'm sure you've seen what happened
at Grant Pharmaceuticals. Like that.
グラント製薬の事件は
ご覧になったはず… あの方法です
（携帯の切れる音）
（ため息）
“武器の使用を許可する”と
通達しろ
Notify officers
deadly force is authorized!
This is Team 1.
Main road blockade complete.
（警官）
こちら１班 県道側の封鎖完了
了解　林道側も完了しました
Roger. Roads into the woods
are also taken care of.
Sending message
（山中(やまなか)）
圭君 行くよ
Let's go, Kei.
（永井圭(ながいけい)）
はーい！
Okay!
Chiba Prefecture
（警官）
ご苦労さまです　荒木さんですね？
Hello, sir. You must be Mr. Araki.
今回は
ご助力を頂き感謝してます
We really appreciate the backup.
何ぶん 亜人に関しては
不慣れなもので…
We're not used to dealing with Ajins here.
It always feels like that
at the beginning.
いや 始めは そんなものですよ
今 亜人管理委員会も
こちらに向かって…
The Ajin Control Commission
is on its way...
（北）
おい！　ちょっと
Hey, you!
賞金は いつ もらえんだ？
１億は？
When do I get my reward?
Where's my hundred mil?!
Huh?
（荒木）
はい？
とぼけんじゃねえ
Don't play dumb!
亜人 とっ捕まえりゃ
１億もらえんだろうが？
I get a reward for catching that Ajin!
Hey, wait! I told you not to do anything
without asking first!
（警官）
ちょっと ちょっと！
勝手に動いちゃ駄目だって
言ったでしょ！
（北）
ああっ！
My apologies, sir.
（警官）
すいません
（北）
触んじゃねぇ！
- Don't touch me!
- Come this way!
（警官）
こっち来なさい
Let go!
（北）
離せ！
That's the informant.
Do you want to hear him out?
通報者の方です　話 聞きますか？
いや 後にしましょう
No, that can wait till later.
Excuse me. I'm Araki. I'm on the Kei
Nagai case with the Saitama Police.
どうも　埼玉県警
永井圭捜査本部の荒木です
状況をお聞かせ願えますか？
- Could you fill me in on the situation?
- Yes, sir.
（警官）
はい
The forest roads and bridge leading
out of the village are already blockaded.
村からの出口である橋と林道は
既に封鎖済みです
それから 村民には―
The villagers will not be allowed
out of their houses.
決して家から出ないよう
徹底してあります
永井の様子は？
What about Nagai?
（警官）
こちらの動きに
気付いている様子はなく―
He doesn't seem
to have noticed our movements.
今は 山中ハナ江(え)さんと一緒です
He's with Hanae Yamanaka right now.
あ… 協力者ですか？
Is that an accomplice?
No, it seems that Nagai has deceived her
into thinking that he's her grandson.
いえ 孫になりすました永井に
騙されているようで
２人を引き離すのは難しいですね
It may be difficult to separate them.
（荒木）
うーん
ちっ… 仕方ないな
Well, it can't be helped.
Let's begin.
始めよう
（セミの鳴き声）
（圭）
ふぅ
雑草なんて
抜いても生えてくるんだから―
Weeds just grow back when you pull them up
anyway, so why not just leave them?
ほっとけばいいんじゃないの？
（山中）
無駄だと分かっててもやるの
それが男ってもんだよ
Even when you know it's no use,
you still do it.
That's what it means to be a man.
はーい
Got it.
（山中）
ああ いたたた…
That hurts.
ふぅ
吉田(よしだ)さん 具合でも悪いのかねぇ
I wonder if Mr. Yoshida's
not feeling well.
（圭）
え？
Huh?
いつもなら 畑にいんのに
Normally he'd be out in the fields.
え？
It's not just Mr. Yoshida.
吉田さんだけじゃないよ
まあ 今日は暑いからね
おおかた 家に引っ込んでんだろ
Well, it's a hot day.
Most people
are probably staying inside.
Begin.
（警官）
始めろ
Grandma, let's go inside
for a minute.
おばあちゃん
いったん 家に帰ろ…
（銃声）
（山中）
え…
ああ…
（隊長）
標的ダウン　確保しろ
Target down. Secure him!
圭君…　圭君！
Ke-Kei, Kei!
（隊長）
撃つな！　民間人がいる
Don't shoot! There's a civilian here!
Stop!
止まれ！
（圭）
声は効果なし　対策は万全
My voice didn't work.
They're well prepared.
くそっ
Damn it.
Sniper team, do you have a shot?
（隊長）
狙撃班 狙えるか？
Sniper Team 1, I have no shot.
（狙撃手）
狙撃１班 不可能です
狙撃２班 同じく
Sniper Team 2, likewise.
There's no point in resisting!
Give up and come quietly, Nagai!
（隊長）
抵抗しても無駄だ！
おとなしく投降しろ 永井！
動くな！
Don't move!
Sorry, Grandma.
ごめんね おばあちゃん
I don't mind.
かまやしないよ
It's kind of cool, like a police drama.
刑事ドラマみたいで
かっこいいじゃないか
フッ ドラマみたいに
逃げ切れればね
As long as I can escape like in a drama.
Don't break the power poles! Stay still!
電柱を壊すな！
おとなしくしてろ！
（圭ＩＢＭ）
黙ってろ
Shut up.
（隊員たち）
おおっ！
（隊員）
うおっ！
What the hell?
（隊員）
な… 何だ？
Take care, Grandma.
（圭）
おばあちゃん 元気でね
（山中）
あっ…
（隊長）
行け！　確保しろ！
Go! Get him!
Follow him! Don't let him get away!
（隊長）
追え！　逃がすな！
（銃声）
（圭）うっ ううっ…
ううっ… ああっ…
（狙撃手）
ぐっ…
ぐぁっ はぁっ はぁっ…
This way!
（隊員）こっちだ！
（隊長）撃て！
（銃声）
出ろ 幽霊！
Come out, ghost!
Damn it! Not ready yet?!
くそっ！　まだか…
I'll never let you catch me,
I'll never let you catch me, I'll never--
追いつかれてたまるか
追いつかれてたまるか 追い…
（銃声）
（圭）うわっ ぐっ… ああ…
ううっ！ ああっ んん…
おっ… はっ！
（隊長）
待て！
Wait!
（隊員）
くそっ どこに行った？
Damn it, where did he go?!
（隊長）
ＩＢＭとやらを使ったんだろう
He must have used that IBM thing.
こちら１班 対象を見失った
Team 1 here. We've lost the target.
Continuing the search.
引き続き 捜索を続ける
（ヘリコプターの音）
はっ！
くそっ
Damn it.
Sato, it's all your fault
that everything's gone to hell!
佐藤さん
あんたのせいでメチャクチャだ
So go and get him. I'm counting on you!
それで取りかかってくれ
頼んだぞ
（警官たち）
はっ！
Yes, sir.
（荒木）
戸崎さん
Mr. Tosaki!
- The current situation is--
- I've heard the report via radio.
現在の状況ですが…
報告は無線で受けています
この後の具体的な動きは？
What exactly are you planning to do next?
We're adding more people
to the search...
（荒木）
今は捜索班を増員し―
永井を見失ったポイントを
重点的に洗わせているところです
...and searching mainly
around where we lost Nagai.
では 彼らを呼び戻してください
Then call them back.
（荒木）
え？
Nagai's not an idiot.
（戸崎）
永井はバカじゃない
I'm sure he's already familiarized himself
with this area.
この山を調べ尽くすくらいのことは
してるはず
個別に追っても
また 逃げられるのがオチです
If you chase him,
he'll just get away again.
（荒木）
あっ はぁ…
I see.
But we have him outnumbered.
…が こちらには数の利がある
ローラー作戦に切り替えるのが
最善でしょう
We could do a clean sweep.
ここから始めて
包囲網を狭めていけば―
If we close in starting from here...
...we're sure to catch him at some point.
必ず どこかで網にかかるはずです
しかし
それでは包囲網が伸び切って―
But if the net is stretched too thin,
he could break through again.
また 突破される恐れが…
No need to worry about that.
その心配はありません
１日に使えるＩＢＭには限度がある
He can only use his IBM
so many times a day.
From what I heard on the report, Nagai
seems to have already used up his quota.
報告によれば 永井は
既に 限度額いっぱい使い切ってる
If we use our numbers,
we won't have any trouble.
数で押せば造作もない
ちっ…
くそっ！
Damn it.
どうする？　どうすればいい？
What should I do? What should I do?!
はっ！
（圭）
携帯なら もらったよ
I took your cell phone.
（中野攻(なかのこう)）
あっ！？
くっ…
（圭）
あいつは
“政府に追われた”って言ってたな
He said the government was after him.
You're going to be of use to me, Nakano.
使わせてもらうぞ 中野
（攻）
うわっ あっ！
ぐはっ…
いってぇ… ああ…
はぁ…
もっかいだ
One more time.
（携帯の着信音）
- What is it?
- We have a lock...
（戸崎）
何だ？
（曽我部）
中野攻の携帯電話が使用され
居場所が判明しました
...on Ko Nakano's cell phone.
Nakano?
（戸崎）
中野？
そっちで処理しろ　今は永井圭の…
Take care of that yourself.
Kei Nagai is--
通話先のエリア
その近くの山中(さんちゅう)です
The phone was used near your location.
（戸崎）
なっ…　永井が潜伏している山か？
Where Nagai is hiding?!
（曽我部）
ええ 偶然とは考えられません
Yes, it can't be a coincidence.
The two of them
must be working together.
２人は行動を共にしていると
考えるのが…
正確な位置情報を送れ！
Send me his exact location!
はい 荒木…
Yes, this is Ara--
あ…
急ぎ向かいます！
I'm on my way!
（泉）
墓穴を掘りましたね
He's dug his own grave.
Maybe Nagai didn't realize
that we knew about Nakano.
永井は
中野がマークされていたことを―
知らないのかも…　あ…
どうしたんです？
- What is it?
- No...
（戸崎）
違う…
やつは ここで生活した痕跡を
一切 残していなかった
He didn't leave a single sign
that he lived here.
（荒木）
こっちだ！　急げ！
This way! Hurry!
He knew that this day would come.
（戸崎）
いつか この日が来ると
確信してたんだ
Someone that smart wouldn't
make a rookie mistake like this.
そこまで頭の切れるやつが―
こんな初歩的なミスを
犯すはずがない
So then...
（泉）
では…
（戸崎）
永井は 中野をおとりにして―
Nagai's using Nakano as a diversion...
自分だけ逃げるつもりだ
...so he can escape by himself.
（攻）
うっ ああ…
ああっ
（荒木）
ここだ　囲め！
We're here! Surround the place!
んんっ… ああっ…
ハハ ざまぁみろ
登ってやったぜ！
How do you like that?!
I made it to the top!
あっ！？　開かねぇのかよ
It won't open!
Damn it!
くそっ！
え…　がぁっ…
よし 突入！
Okay, go!
あっ ああ…
あっ！？
（荒木）
動くな！　両手を…
Don't move! Put your hands--
は？
The southern part of Chiba Prefecture
should expect north winds...
（携帯音声:アナウンス）
千葉県南部の今夜は―
北の風のち東の風
晴れのち曇りでしょう
...then later easterly winds,
and clear skies followed by clouds.
（圭）はぁっ
（攻）はぁっ はぁっ…
Hurry! I'm sure they'll
have noticed by now!
急げ！
やつらも もう気付いてるはずだ
- If they surround us again, it's over!
- Then what are we gonna do?!
もっかい 包囲されたら終わりだ！
じゃあ どうすんだよ？
It's risky, but we'll have
to take the shortest route!
リスクは高いが最短距離を行く！
ああ？
この先に脱出ポイントがある
そこまで行けば 僕らの勝ちだ
There's an escape point this way!
If we can make it that far, we've won!
あっ！
（刺さる音）
（攻）うわっ
（圭）
あっ…
（攻）
うあっ…
ううっ…
あっ！
（戸崎）
意外だな　中野は
おとりに使ったんじゃないのか？
This is unexpected. You weren't
using Nakano as a diversion?
１人なら
逃げ切れていたかもしれんのに
You might have escaped on your own.
Too bad.
残念だったな
くっ！
（戸崎）
今夜は解剖台で眠るといい
You'll be sleeping
on the dissection table tonight.
Number 3...
003番
永井圭
Kei Nagai.
（銃声）
（圭）うっ…
く… くそ…
Damn... it...
なんで… 僕… ばっかり…
Why... me...?
なんで…
Why...?
Okay, take him.
（戸崎）
よし 捕獲しろ
ＩＢＭの心配はない
There's no need to worry about his IBM.
Damn... you...
ふざ… けんな…
You, damn...
ふざ… けん…
No!
（圭ＩＢＭ）
嫌だぁー！
あっ
（隊員たちのどよめき）
ど… どうなってる！？
Wh-- What's going on?!
（戸崎）
なぜ ＩＢＭが？
Why is his IBM...?
（隊員）
シ… シールド！
Shields!
（隊員たち）
うわっ！
Stand back.
下がってください
なんて ムチャクチャな…
It's out of control.
くっ…　戸崎さん 下がって！
Mr. Tosaki, get back!
あっ
（戸崎）
眠らせても止まらないなら…
- If putting him to sleep won't stop it...
- Mr. Tosa--
戸崎さ…
（悲鳴）
（銃声）
Then I'll just have to kill him.
殺すまでだ！
Is it not Nagai's?!
永井のじゃないのか！？
（銃声）
違う…　殺しても駄目なのか？
No... even killing him wont' stop it?!
Serves you right.
（圭ＩＢＭ）
ざまあみろ
うっ
（泉）
戸崎さん！
Mr. Tosaki!
（圭）うわぁっ！
（殴る音）
（銃声）
（戸崎）
捕獲しろ！
Catch them!
（泉）
クロちゃん！
Kuro!
幽霊！？
政府側に亜人がいるのか？
A ghost?! The government
has an Ajin on their side?!
くっ！
うう…
Stay put!
行くな！
あっ…
そんな…　すぐに出せるはず…
No... He shouldn't be able
to call it again so soon!
ない！
はぁっ はぁっ…
もっかいだ 幽霊！
One more time, ghost!
ああっ…
He can't!
まさか！？
It's not possible...
ありえん…
（泉）
でも 同時には出せないはず！
He can't call two at once!
あっ… あいつ！
- Hey, where'd he...!
- Over here, Nagai!
（攻）
こっちだ 永井！
You're too slow!
遅(おせ)ぇって！
（圭）
うっさいな！
Shut up!
（銃声）
（攻）うわっ！
あ… ヘヘ… ああ…
（爆発音）
（隊員たち）うおっ！
ぐっ…
After the incident the other day
at Grant Pharmaceuticals...
（キャスター）
先日のグラント製薬の事件に
引き続き―
...the police have once again failed
to capture an Ajin...
警察は またしても
亜人の確保に至らず
責任の追及は免れないと見られます
...and an internal investigation
is expected.
The Coast Guard
is currently searching Tokyo Bay...
（泉）
現在 海上保安庁が―
東京湾を捜索中ですが
...but they haven't found Nagai or Nakano.
永井と中野の発見には
至ってないようです
（北）
離せ！
Let me go!
お前らじゃラチが明かねぇ！
You guys are a waste of my time!
あっ おい あんた
Hey, you, what's up with my reward?!
When do I get it!?
賞金は どうなってる？
いつ もらえんだ？
Reward?
賞金？
You can't give me nothing
just 'cause you let him get away!
逃がしたからゼロってのは
筋が通らねぇぞ
You gotta give me at least half!
半分くれぇは
出してもらわねぇとな！
（笑い声）
Money, huh?
金か…
うっ… な… 何がおかしい！？
What's so funny?!
The idea of a reward for finding Ajins
is nothing more than a rumor.
亜人に賞金が出るというのは
単なるデマですよ
But I've heard you may get a thank-you
letter from the local police.
ただ 通報に関しては―
後日 地元警察署から
感謝状が贈られると思いますが
デ… デマ？
A rumor...?
（戸崎）
行くぞ 下村君
Let's go, Shimomura.
（北）
うう… ああ… おい…
永井の実験データを
オグラ博士に渡しておけ
Send the experimental data
on Nagai to Dr. Ogura.
やつは 帽子とも田中とも
全くの別物だ
He's completely different
from the Hat or Tanaka.
Yes, sir.
はい
（攻）
外国に行っちゃったりしてな
What if we end up in another country?
（圭）
インドじゃ亜人は
崇拝されてるらしいよ
Apparently they venerate Ajins in India.
（攻）
え？ “すーはい”って何？
マージャン用語？
Venerate? What's that?
Like a move in mah-jongg?
（圭）
ちっ…
（ため息）
で どうすんだ？　どこ逃げる？
So, what's the plan?
Where are we gonna run to?
逃げるのは終わりだ　佐藤を止める
I'm done running. I'm going to stop Sato.
えっ？
ああっ…
準備はいいか？
Are you ready?
（攻）
ヘッ 俺は大丈夫だ
I'm all set.
Let's go.
（圭）
行くぞ
（攻）
ぬあっ！
（奥山(おくやま)）
はい アクション
Okay, action.
今日 私は
第２ウエーブの開始を決意した
Today, I've decided to start Wave 2.
Humans are not hesitating
to further oppress us Ajins.
人間は省みることなく―
我々 亜人への弾圧を
加速させている
第２ウエーブのテーマは“浄化”だ
The theme of Wave 2 is "cleansing."
これは陰謀に加担した組織の
主要な面々のリストだ
This is a list of the principal figures
in the conspiracy against us.
我々は この15名を暗殺する
We will assassinate
these 15 people.
もし 第２ウエーブ終了までに―
If the country doesn't reconsider
its oppression of Ajins...
国が 亜人弾圧の姿勢を
改めていなかった場合
...by the end of Wave 2...
我々は第３ウエーブへと駒を進める
...we will move on to Wave 3.
第３…
Wave 3...
That will be the final wave.
それが最終ウエーブだ
私が この国を統治する
I will take over the country.
If my wish would come true
願い叶(かな)うなら
もう一度
Once again
I wanna touch your heart
君の心に
触れていたい
No matter how dark it gets
どんな闇でも
探してるんだ
I'll be searching
For my one
たったひとつの
光を
And only light
As I look up to the stars
Even though you are far
遠いけど
You're looking up at the same starry sky
同じ星空　見上げてる
In the sky of my heart
心の空には
雫(こぼ)れ落ちそうな
It's about to spill over
Your smile and
君の笑顔と
ぬくもり
Your warmth
Hear me
Until I went away and
Faced the lonely days
愛することの意味なんて
I thought I could understand
What it means to love
分かってたつもりだった
Feeling everything that
Was right in front of me
大切なもの失って
Losing something precious
Realizing real love
本当の愛に気付いて
I'll tell you now
I'll tell you now,
Just how close you are